# Research Assistant Professor IMDEA Software Institute, Madrid, Spain ⊠ niki.vazou@imdea.org https://nikivazou.github.io/

# Niki Vazou

My reseach brings formal verification on programming languages. Mostly, I work on Liquid Haskell, a refinement type checker for Haskell programs. I have 7 papers on CORE A\* (flagship) conferences (2 ICFP, 2 POPL, 1 PLDI and 2 OOSPLA). My h-index is 9, I have 551 citations, and I am an active member of the Programming Languages community having served to 18 committees and (co-) chaired seven venues.

	Education & Positions
2018-present	Research Assistant Professor
	IMDEA Software Institute, Madrid, Spain
2017-2018	Postdoctoral Fellow in Programming Languages Group
	Department of Computer Science, University of Maryland
2011-2016	PhD in Programming Systems Group (GPA: $3.962 / 4$ )
	Department of Computer Science & Engineering, University of California, San Diego
	Fellowships & Awards
2019	Atraccion de Talento Fellowship, Madrid
2017	Victor Basili Postdoctoral Fellowship, UMD
2015	UCSD CSE Graduate Award for Research
2014	Microsoft Research Graduate Research Fellowship
	Internships
Summer 2016	Awake Networks, Mountain View, USA.
Summer 2014	Microsoft Research, Redmond, USA.
Fall 2013	Microsoft Research, Cambridge, UK.
Summer 2012	Opa, Paris, French.
	Teaching Experience
Fall 2019	Course: Advanced Functional Programming Languages, UPM, Spain.
Winter 2018	Course CMSC330: Organization of Programming Languages, UMD, USA.
Fall 2017	Course CMSC498V: Advanced Functional Programming Languages, UMD, USA.
	Supervision
2018-now	Panagiotis Bougoulias, PhD Candidate, IMDEA.
2018-2020	James Parker, PhD, UMD.
2020	Mustafa Hafidi, Master Thesis, IMDEA.
2020-now	Zack Grannan, Intern, IMDEA.

2019 Stefan Malewski, Intern, IMDEA.

## Publications

- Y. Liu, J. Parker, P. Redmond, L. Kuper, M. Hicks, and N. Vazou. Verifying Replicated Data Types with Typeclass Refinements in Liquid Haskell. OOPSLA, 2020.
- J. Parker, **N. Vazou**, and M. Hicks. Information Flow Security for Multi-Tier Web Applications. POPL, 2019.
- M. Kazerounian, S. N. Guria, N. Vazou, J. Foster, D. Van Horn. Type-Level Computations for Ruby Libraries. PLDI, 2019.
- N. Vazou, E. Tanter, and D. Van Horn. Gradual Liquid Type Inference. OOPSLA, 2018. Best Paper Award
- N. Vazou, A. Tondwalkar, V. Choudhury, R. Newton, P. Wadler, and R. Jhala. Refinement Reflection: Complete Verification with SMT. POPL, 2018
- N. Vazou, A. Bourgerie, J. S. Foster, E. Torlak. Refinement Types for Ruby. VMCAI, 2018.
- N. Vazou, J. Breitner, R. Kunkel, D. Van Horn, and G. Hutton. Theorem Proving for All. Haskell Symposium, 2018.
- N. Vazou, L. Lampropoulos, and J. Polakow. A Tale of Two Provers. Haskell Symposium, 2017.
- N. Vazou, and D. Leijen. From Monads to Effects and Back. PADL 2016.
- N. Vazou, A. Bakst, and R. Jhala. Bounded Refinement Types. ICFP, 2015.
- E. Seidel, N. Vazou, and R. Jhala. Type Targeted Testing. ESOP, 2015.
- N. Vazou, E. Seidel, R. Jhala, D. Vytiniotis, and S. Peyton-Jones. Refinement Types for Haskell. ICFP, 2014.
- N. Vazou, E. Seidel, and R. Jhala. LiquidHaskell: Experience with Refinement Types in the Real World. Haskell, 2014.
- N. Vazou, P. Rondon, and R. Jhala. Abstract Refinement Types. ESOP, 2013.

### Committee Member

PEPM'21, CAV'20, FCS'20, TFP'20, POPL'19, ESOP'18, Haskell Symposium'18, ICFP'18, Haskell in Leipzig'17, ML-Family Workshop'17, Scala Symposium'17, PADL'17, Haskell Impementors' Workshop'16, Haskell Symposium'16, Haskell in Leipzig'16, Scala Symposium'16, PADL'16, TFP'16.

### Organizations

Co-Chair, Artifact Evaluation, PLDI 2020.

Virtualization Committee, POPL, 2020.

Co-Chair, Student Research Compatition, POPL 2019, 2020.

Chair, Haskell Implementors' Workshop 2019.

Co-Chair, Programming Languages and Analysis for Security, 2019.

Co-Organizer, Programming Languages Mentoring Workshop, ICFP, 2018.

Co-Chair, Workshop on Type-Driven Development, 2018.

Member of Haskell.org Committee 2016-2020.

Updated

September 2020